- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[ukulele music]
[尤克里里音乐]
♪ ♪
- Howdy neighbor.
- 邻居你好。
It's your old pal Sandy Cheeks
这是你的老朋友桑迪·奇克斯
with a true to life tale
direct from Bikini Bottom.
有一个真实的故事
直接从比基尼底部。
It's the end of
another long day,
结束了
又是漫长的一天，
and every critter in town is
getting ready to hit the hay.
镇上的每一个小动物都是
准备好上干草了。
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
Whoo-hoo.
[snores]
呼呼。
[打鼾]
- Even little old
SpongeBob and Gary
- 即使年纪不大
海绵宝宝和加里
are laying down
their weary heads.
正在躺下
他们疲惫的头脑。
- [grunts]
Night Gare-bear.
- [咕哝]
夜车熊。
[yawns]
[哈欠]
- Now snails love to sleep
- 现在蜗牛喜欢睡觉了
but they also like
to have their fun.
但他们也喜欢
享受他们的乐趣。
And clever little Gary
here is no different.
还有聪明的小加里
这里也不例外。
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
With a dang nifty
decoy in place
非常俏皮
诱饵就位
Gary is ready
to hit the town.
加里准备好了
去镇上。
But first things first.
但首先要说的是。
That gooey little
varmint is mighty hungry.
那个软乎乎的小
恶鼠非常饥饿。
[chuckles] It may not
look like much to you and me
[笑]可能不会
对你我来说看起来很重要
but this here is
four-star dining to a snail.
但这是
四星级的餐厅给了一只蜗牛。
[laughs]
[笑]
Now, Gary never minds
running into a friend
现在，加里不在乎
遇到一个朋友
but old Patrick here don't
seem ready to share his meal.
但这里的老帕特里克不
似乎准备好分享他的饭菜了。
- [growls]
- [yelps]
- [咆哮]
- [尖叫声]
- [growling]
- [whimpering]
- [咆哮]
- [呜咽]
- [barking]
- [吠叫]
- [roaring]
- [咆哮]
- [whimpering]
- [呜咽]
- Ol' Gary feels as big as
a ten-point buck right now,
- 老加里感觉和
现在十块钱，
but he's about to be reminded
但他即将被提醒
that life ain't
all fun and games.
那生活不是
所有的乐趣和游戏。
Especially when animal
control is on your tail.
尤其是当动物
控制权就在你的尾巴上。
[exciting music]
[激动人心的音乐]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Freeze, slime ball!
冻结，粘液球！
- [meows]
- [喵]
- Hmm?
[growls]
- 唔？
[咆哮]
[warbling]
[颤音]
[crash]
[碰撞]
♪ ♪
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[choking]
[窒息]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- As much as Gary likes
getting one over on the heat
- 加里喜欢多少就多少
热度一过
he has more important matters
to attend to.
他有更重要的事情
去参加。
- [straining]
- [紧张]
- This here is old Plankton's
restaurant, the Chum Bucket.
- 这是老浮游生物的
餐厅，Chum Bucket。
Gary ain't here
for vittles, though.
加里不在这里
不过，为了维特。
No one's ever at
the Chum Bucket for vittles.
从来没有人在
食物桶。
[mischievous music]
[恶作剧的音乐]
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
♪ ♪
[gurgling, coughing]
[咯咯声、咳嗽声]
[snoring]
[打鼾]
- [exhales]
- [呼气]
- That there's spot.
- 有位置。
Plankton's pet amoeba,
and Gary's best friend.
浮游生物的宠物阿米巴原虫，
和加里最好的朋友。
- Psst.
- [barking]
- 嘘。
- [吠叫]
- Spot's cute...
- 斑点很可爱...
but about as dumb
as a barrel of hair.
但同样愚蠢
作为一桶头发。
Gary better think quick
or they'll both be busted
加里最好快点思考
否则他们都会被抓
before there
night's even begun.
在那之前
夜晚已经开始了。
- [meows]
- [barking]
- [喵]
- [吠叫]
- Ough.
- 哎呀。
[snoring]
[打鼾]
- Ol' Gary and Spot have
been sneaking out for ages
- Ol' Gary 和 Spot 有
已经偷偷溜出去好多年了
though their owners
are none the wiser.
虽然他们的主人
没有人更明智。
[both chattering]
[giggles]
[两人都在喋喋不休]
[咯咯笑]
They love playing all
sorts of games together,
他们都喜欢玩
一起玩各种游戏，
but their doggone favorite
is wrestling.
但他们最喜欢的
正在摔跤。
[excited chatter]
[兴奋的喋喋不休]
- It's the
Krusty Krab kitchen.
- 这是
蟹堡王厨房。
- [meowing]
- What a stroke of luck.
- [喵喵叫]
- 真是太幸运了。
Gary and Spot must have
worked up quite an appetite
加里和斯波必须有
胃口大开
with all them fun and games.
充满乐趣和游戏。
[accordion music]
[手风琴音乐]
- [meows]
- [喵]
- Uh oh.
That ice box is locked up
- 呃哦。
那个冰盒是锁着的
tighter than a horse
thief in a hoosegow.
比马还紧
hoosegow 中的小偷。
- [barking]
- [吠叫]
♪ ♪
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[yelps]
[尖叫声]
[whines]
[哀鸣]
- Oh boy.
It's chow time.
- 哦，孩子。
吃顿饭的时间到了
- [yowls]
- [嚎叫]
- [meows]
- [喵]
[light music]
[轻音乐]
- [barks]
- [吠叫]
- [straining]
- [紧张]
[SpongeBob laugh]
[海绵宝宝笑]
- [barks]
- [吠叫]
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
- [barking]
- [吠叫]
- [humming]
- Whoo-whee.
- [嗡嗡声]
- 呼呼。
Looks like Gary
is cooking up some fun.
看起来像加里
正在做饭一些乐趣。
- [chattering]
- [喋喋不休]
[bell dings]
[铃声]
- [yelps]
- [尖叫声]
- [chattering excitedly]
- [ barking]
- [兴奋地叽叽喳喳]
- [吠叫]
- It may not be pretty
- 可能不太漂亮
but to a critter,
chow is chow.
但对于一个小动物来说，
周就是周。
♪ ♪
- [barking]
- [meowing]
- [吠叫]
- [喵喵叫]
- Come out, come out.
- 出来吧，出来吧。
[gasps]
Oh, there you are.
[喘气]
哦，你来了。
[both chattering]
[两人都在喋喋不休]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]
- [grunts]
Ow.
- [咕哝]
噢。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Ha ha! I've got you this time.
哈哈！这次我有你了
[warbling]
[颤音]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[sad trombone music]
[悲伤的长号音乐]
- Ahem.
- [grunts]
- 咳咳。
- [咕哝]
Animal control, citizen.
I'm hunting an errant snail.
动物控制，公民。
我正在寻找一只迷路的蜗牛。
- I don't give
a sea fig about snails.
- 我不给
关于蜗牛的海无花果。
You tripped my silent alarm!
你触发了我的无声警报！
Just look at this mess!
看看这烂摊子吧！
Take that you varmint!
- [warbling]
就拿你这个恶棍来说吧！
- [颤音]
- Take that!
- 拿着那个！
[grunting]
- Ow! Ow! Ow!
[咕噜声]
- 噢！噢！噢！
- [giggles]
Looks like our boys
- [咯咯笑]
看起来像我们的男孩
gave Johnny law
the slip again.
给了约翰尼·劳
再次滑倒。
Reckon they're gonna need some
place to lay low for a while.
估计他们需要一些
暂时低调的地方。
- [both]
Phew.
- [两者]
唷。
- Uh oh.
- 呃哦。
Looks like their hiding
spot's all ready occupado.
看起来他们隐藏着
现场已准备就绪。
Luckily for them,
Gary and Spot
对他们来说幸运的是，
加里和斯波特
are all ready pals
with everyone here.
都准备好了朋友们
和这里的每个人。
- Let's get this party started!
- 让我们开始这个派对吧！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[dance music playing]
[all laughing and cheering]
[舞曲演奏]
[大家欢笑和欢呼]
♪ ♪
- Uh oh.
- 呃哦。
Looks like the fuzz
ain't gonna give up so easy.
看起来像毛茸茸的
不会那么容易放弃的
- Hey, this is my Jam.
- 嘿，这是我的果酱。
- They say that music
soothes the savage beast.
- 他们说音乐
安抚野蛮的野兽。
- Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
Oh, yeah.
- 哦，是的。哦，是的。
哦，是的。
- But sometimes it works
on knuckle heads too.
- 但有时它会起作用
指节头上也有。
- That's how you do it.
- 你就是这样做的。
You do it.
你做吧。
[warbles, grunts]
[颤音，咕噜声]
[record scratches,
glass shatters]
[记录划痕，
玻璃碎裂]
Uh, you animals
are under arrest.
呃，你们这些动物
已被捕。
[all growling]
Uh...
[全都咆哮]
呃...
Uh oh.
[all grunting]
呃哦。
[全都咕哝]
- Youch.
That's gotta hurt.
- 尤奇。
那一定很痛吧
Oh mama.
哦妈妈。
[both whimpering]
[两人都呜咽]
[playful music]
[俏皮的音乐]
[all growling]
[全都咆哮]
- [strains, grunts]
- [紧张，咕哝声]
[all grunt]
[全都咕哝]
- [yawns]
- [哈欠]
[grunts, hums]
[咕哝声，哼哼声]
- I guess this party
just got pooped.
- 我猜这个派对
刚刚拉屎了。
[ominous tone]
[不祥的语气]
- [crying]
- Luckily,
- [哭泣]
- 幸运的是，
SpongeBob's little Gare-Bear
海绵宝宝的小车站熊
always has something
under his shell.
总是有一些东西
在他的壳下。
- [meows]
- [喵]
- Locked doors
are never a problem
- 锁着的门
从来都不是问题
for a snail like Gary.
对于像加里这样的蜗牛。
- [spits]
- [吐口水]
- [grunts, squeaks]
- [咕哝声，吱吱声]
[mischievous music]
[恶作剧的音乐]
♪ ♪
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
- Now to most animals
the pound is scarier
- 现在对大多数动物来说
英镑更可怕
than a bob cat
in your long johns.
比鲍勃猫
在你的长裤里。
But Gary and Spot our on a
mission to save their pals.
但是加里和斯波我们在
拯救他们的朋友的使命。
[both grunting, straining]
[两人都咕哝着，紧张着]
♪ ♪
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- Aha!
- 啊哈！
[exciting music]
[激动人心的音乐]
- [yips]
- [哎呀]
[squeaks]
[吱吱声]
♪ ♪
all: Huh?
全体：啊？
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
- [meows softly]
Shh.
- [轻声喵喵叫]
嘘。
[all grunt]
[全都咕哝]
[tense music]
[紧张的音乐]
- Hmm?
- 唔？
- Oh, Marvin,
- 哦，马文，
you could catch every snail
in Bikini Bottom
你可以抓住每只蜗牛
比基尼下装
but the only thing
you've really caught
但唯一的事情
你真的抓住了
is loneliness.
是孤独。
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
[coughing]
[咳嗽]
And kennel cough.
还有犬窝咳。
- Marvin here ain't
kith nor kin to Gary
- 马文不在这里
加里的亲戚
but that don't matter none.
但这并不重要。
Gary could never bear
to see anyone looking so down.
加里永远无法忍受
看到有人如此低落。
- I need another snot rag.
- 我需要另一块鼻涕抹布。
[somber ukulele music]
[忧郁的尤克里里音乐]
- [meowing]
- [喵喵叫]
[all grunt]
[全都咕哝]
- [sobs]
- [抽泣]
Hey!
How did you animals get out?
嘿！
你们这些动物是怎么逃出来的？
[soft music]
[轻音乐]
Wh-wh-what's going on?
什、什、这是怎么回事？
♪ ♪
- Viola.
- 维奥拉。
[grinding]
[研磨]
[exhales, giggles]
[呼气，咯咯笑]
- [gasps]
She's beautiful.
- [喘气]
她很漂亮。
[sighs]
[叹气]
[laughs]
[笑]
[excited shouting]
[兴奋的喊叫]
[both grumbling]
[两人都抱怨]
[light music]
[轻音乐]
- Oh!
That's so good!
- 哦！
那太好了！
[sighs]
[叹气]
[organ music]
[管风琴音乐]
I do.
我愿意。
[kissing]
[all cheering]
[接吻]
[大家欢呼]
- [laughs goofily]
- [傻笑]
I can't thank you all enough.
我对你们感激不尽。
You brought love
into my lonely life.
你带来了爱
走进我孤独的生活。
Everybody's free to go.
大家都可以自由活动了
[cheering]
[欢呼]
- [laughing]
Why am I running?
- [笑]
我为什么要跑步？
- With their friends rescued,
- 他们的朋友获救后，
it's time for our boys
to finally get some shut eye.
现在是我们男孩的时间了
终于可以闭上眼睛了。
[light music]
[轻音乐]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
[barks]
[吠叫]
♪ ♪
- [grumbling]
- [抱怨]
- [meows]
- [喵]
- After his long night
of adventuring
- 在漫长的一夜之后
冒险的
Gary is more tired than
a bronco on busting day.
加里比他更累
野马在破坏日。
[fog horn]
[雾号]
- [gasps]
Come on Gary, you lazybones.
- [喘气]
来吧，加里，你们这些懒骨头。
It's time to wake up.
是时候醒来了。
- [yawns]
- [哈欠]
- Oh well, maybe a few
more minutes wouldn't hurt.
- 哦，好吧，也许有一些
再多几分钟也没什么坏处。
- Well, that's
the long and short of it.
- 嗯，那就是
它的长和短。
See ya'll next time
for more true to life tales
下次见
更多贴近生活的故事
of Bikini Bottom.
的比基尼底部。
- Shhh.
- [growls]
- 嘘。
- [咆哮]
[placid ukulele music]
[平静的尤克里里音乐]
♪ ♪